Zhaoxuan Tan

Address: Pengkang Building 206, 28 Xianning W Rd, Xi'an, China

Email: tanzhaoxuan@stu.xjtu.edu.cn Homepage: tamsiuhin.github.io Last updated: April 19, 2022

Research Interests

I am broadly interested in graph neural networks, knowledge graph, social network analysis, natural language processing and graph mining in general. Previous research of Twitter bot detection has been accepted at AAAI 2022 and now working on knowledge graph representation learning.

Education

Xi'an Jiaotong University, Xi'an, Shaanxi, China (member of the C9 league in China) 2019.8-present

B.S. in Computer Science and Technology

GPA: 90.08/100 (Transcript), rank 11th among 164 students

Advisor: Minnan Luo

Publications

[1] Heterogeneity-aware Twitter Bot Detection with Relational Graph Transformers.

Shangbin Feng, Zhaoxuan Tan, Rui Li, and Minnan Luo.

2022 AAAI Conference on Artificial Intelligence (AAAI), 2022. [15% acceptance rate]

[2] Legislator Representation Learning with Social Context and Expert Knowledge.

Shangbin Feng, **Zhaoxuan Tan**, Zilong Chen, Peisheng Yu, Qinghua Zheng, Xiaojun Chang, Minnan Luo. arXiv preprint arXiv:2110.12906 (2021).

Honors and Awards

AAAI Student Scholarship, Association for the Advancement of Artificial Intelligence	2022
National Second Prize, Contemporary Undergraduate Mathematical Contest in Modeling	2021
Scholarship for Outstanding Students, Second Prize (rank $11/164$), Xi'an Jiaotong University	2021
Dean's List, Xi'an Jiaotong University	2021
Top Project Runner Up, NUS SoC Summer Workshop	2021
Honorable Mentioned Prize (top 15%), Mathematical Contest in Modeling (MCM)	2021
Scholarship for Outstanding Students, Second Prize (rank 39/1200), Xi'an Jiaotong University	2020
First Prize in Shaanxi Province, Contemporary Undergraduate Mathematical Contest in Modeling	2020
Dean's List, Xi'an Jiaotong University	2020

Experience

Research Intern, Knowledge Engineering Group (KEG), Tsinghua University 2022.4-present

Large-scale knowledge graph completion and reasoning with language model.

Advisor: Yuxiao Dong @ Tsinghua University, China

Member of LUD (Luo lab Undergraduate Division), Xi'an Jiaotong University 2021.8-present

Researcher at the **LUD lab**, focusing on graph-based Twitter bot detection and knowledge graph embedding learning. One second-author conference paper of Twitter bot detection got accepted at AAAI 2022.

Advisor: Minnan Luo @ Xi'an Jiaotong University, China

Summer Workshop, National University of Singapore (virtual) 2021.5-2021.7

Attend lectures in Al analytics and IoT, build a Twitter bot detection demo.

Advisor: Lek Hsiang Hui @ National University of Singapore, Singapore

Information-technology Talent Program, Xi'an Jiaotong University

2020.11-2021.10

Bulid a UAV formation control system, learn basic reinforcement learning algorithm

Advisor: Liangjun Ke @ Xi'an Jiaotong University, China

Skills

Programming Languages:

-Proficient: Python, MATLAB, C/C++ -Capable: Bash, HTML/CSS, Javascript

Tools and Frameworks: Pytorch, LATEX, Visual Studio, MobaXTerm, Git, ssh, Vim Natural Languages: Mandarin (native), English (fluent), Cantonese (native)